Guide to the General Collection Manuscript Music Miscellany
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912
  - Music
    - Souvenirs d'enfance
      - "Souvenirs d'enfance / poésie d'Hégésippe Moreau; mélodie pour ténor par Jules Massenet", 1863 Aug; 1 ms. score ([3] p.) + 1 ms. part ([1] p.); 36 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 11)
        Score, holograph, with dedication to Frank [Sirop?].
        Voice part includes text for the second and third verses.
    - Verger
      Song, with text by Camille Distel.
      Published 1872?, as part of op. 2, 1872.
      - "Le verger: (ancienne chansonnette)", 1872 Feb 18; 1 ms. score (1 p.); 36 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 12)
        Score, holograph, with printer's markings, dated at Paris.
    - Werther
      Opera, with libretto by Edouard Blau, Paul Milliet, and Georges Hartmann, based on Die Leiden des jungen Werther, by Johann Wolfgang von Goethe.
      First performed 1892; published 1892.
      - Quotation from Werther, n.d.; 1 item (1 sheet); 14 x 21 cm., bound in volume, 31 cm. (Box FOLDER 199)
        Excerpt from the prelude, showing melody only.
        Captioned by Massenet: "Le jardin de 'Charlotte' à Wetzlar, Juin 1793," signed, and inscribed to Lily [Jumel?].
        Bound with: Two engraved portraits; ALS to an unidentified recipient; and Salutaris.
    - Unidentified
      - Copies of music by other composers, 1864; 7 ms. scores (Box Folder 188)
        Copies made by Massenet while a student in Rome. Music includes Stabat mater for eight voices by Palestrina, from a copy annotated by Richard Wagner, and works by Bach, Handel, Schubert, and others. Some items are dated at end, Rome, 1864 Jul-Oct.
      - "Nocturne", [ca. 1900-1910]; 1 ms. score (4 p.); 33 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 14)
        Draft, with revisions, for an orchestral work, probably dating from late in Massenet's life.
        On verso of last page: "Nocturne, esquisse d'orchestre".
        Formerly owned by Juliette Massenet and Léon Bessand.
      - "Salutaris: composé pour solo (contralto ou mezzo soprano), choeur 3 voix égal (soprano, mezzo soprano, contralto), avec accompagnement d'orgue ou de piano / par Jules Massenet; réduction de l'orchestra", 1 ms. score ([1], 6 p.); 31 cm., bound in volume, 31 cm. (Box FOLDER 199)
        Score, signed on t.p., in caption, and at end.
        In Latin.
        Bound with: Two engraved portraits; ALS to an unidentified recipient; and Quotation from Werther.
      - Unidentified fragment, n.d.; 1 ms. score fragment (1 leaf); 36 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 13)
        Fragment from a vocal work scored for two voices and piano. The fragment is signed by Juliette Massenet, 1913 May, and accompanied by an ALS from her, Paris, 1913 May 10, to "Monsieur," possibly the husband of Marie Kohn, enclosing the music in response to a request for her father's holograph.
        First line of text: "Tout homme dans Rome nous fuit et la ville servile toujours obéit".
      - "Valse très lent / J. Massenet", n.d.; 1 ms. score ([6] p.); 38 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 15)
        Score, copyist's manuscript.
        For orchestra.
  - Other Papers
    - "A Massenet, " poem by vicomte Henri de Bornier, 1898 Oct 14; 1 item (1 p.); 21 x 31 cm. (Box Folder 189)
      Fair copy in Bornier's holograph. Annotated: "Séance de la Société des auteurs dramatiques".
    - "A Massenet, ses eleves, 1878-1896", [ca. 1896]; 1 v. ([3] leaves); 26 cm. (Box Folder 190)
      Commemorative book, inscribed to Massenet by his students, in honor of his appointment as Commandeur of the Légion d'Honneur. Signatures include: André Bloch, Alfred Bruneau, Bernard-Louis Crocé-Spinelli, Georges Guiraud, Fernand Halphen, Edouard Hillemacher, Lucien Joseph, Charles Koechlin, Georges Marty, Max d'Ollone, Henri Rabaud, Augustin Savard, and Charles Silver. Other subscribers listed in an unidentified hand include: Herman Bemberg, Gustave Charpentier, Georges Enesco, Reynaldo Hahn, Xavier Leroux, Charles Levadé, Charles Malherbe, Joseph Guy Marie Ropartz, Florent Schmitt, Julien Tiersot, and Paul Vidal.
      Binding: morocco decorated in gilt; vellum leaves.
      Volume includes five blank leaves.
    - "Discours prononcé par M. Massenet à l'inauguration du monument d'Ernest Reyer, au Lavandou", [ca. 1909-1912]; 1 item (10 p.); 22 x 28 cm. (Box Folder 193)
      Speech, manuscript fair copy, in an unidentified hand.
    - "Déclaration de nationalité", 1889 Apr 8; 1 item (1 p.); 22 x 28 cm. (Box Folder 192)
      Printed form completed and signed by Massenet, stating name, date and place of birth, and nationality.
    - "Esclarmonde", 1911; 1 item (9 p.); 31 cm. (Box Folder 194)
      Draft of an essay by Massenet, signed, about Sibyl Sanderson and her performance in Esclarmonde, published in L'écho de Paris, 1911 Mar 26. A revised version of the essay was published in Massenet's Mes souvenirs (Paris: P. Lafitte, c1912).
    - "Hérodiade", c1911; 1 item (11 leaves); 32 cm., bound in volume, 38 cm. (Box Volume 8)
      Draft of an essay by Massenet, revised, signed, describing creation of the opera, published in L'écho de Paris, 1912. A revised version of the essay was published in Massenet's Mes souvenirs (Paris: P. Lafitte, c1912).
      Date from copyright annotation.
    - Death announcement, [1912 Aug]; 1 item (1 sheet); 27 cm. (Box Folder 191)
      Printed sheet issued by the Massenet family, announcing the death of Jules Massenet.
    - Engravings of JM, n.d.; 2 prints: engraving; 25.3 x 16.8 cm. and smaller, bound in volume, 31 cm. (Box FOLDER 199)
      Two engraved portraits, made by Cliché Eug. Pirou, Paris, from a photograph; and by Guillaume et fils, from a drawing with signature.
      Bound with ALS to an unidentified recipient; Quotation from Werther; and Salutaris.
    - Passport for travel to Barcelona, 1881 Apr 13; 1 item (2 p.); 42 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 16)
      Printed form, completed in manuscript in an unidentified hand, including a physical description of Massenet, with signatures of Massenet and French officials.
      On verso: stamp of the French consulate in Barcelona, 1881 Apr 19.
    - Photograph of JM, 1889; 1 photograph: carte-de-visite, b w; 10.2 x 6.3 cm. (Box Folder 195)
      Portrait, made by Chalot, Paris.
      Annotated by Massenet: "1889 (Esclarmonde)".
    - Photograph of JM, n.d.; 1 photograph: b w; in frame, 14.1 x 14.5 cm. (Box Folder 196)
      Portrait made late in his life.
    - Photograph of JM, 1903 Oct; 1 photograph: b w; in frame, 25.5 x 19.5 cm. (Box Folder 197)
      Portrait made by Varischi, Artico, & Co., Milan.
      Inscribed by Massenet to Louise Massenet, "au retour de 'Thaïs' en Italie".
    - Photograph of JM, n.d.; 1 photograph: b w; 20.7 x 26.0 cm., on mount 24.2 x 29.3 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 17)
      Portrait, made in his study.
    - Photographs of JM, [1912]; 3 photographs: b w; 17.9 x 13.0 cm. (Box Folder 198)
      Three portrait photographs made in his home, Rue Vaugirard, Paris.
      Stamp on versos: "Photographie A. Harlingue, Paris".
      Two photographs are captioned on verso in an unidentified hand.
    - Photographs of JM, n.d.; 2 photographs: b w; 12.8 x 9.4 cm. and smaller. (Box FOLDER 200)
      Two portraits, including a photographic postcard made by Boyer, Paris.
      Bound with: ALS to George Durrieu, 1909 Jul 4; three ALS to unidentified, n.d., 1903 Feb 5, and 1911 May 24; two visiting cards with ANS to unidentified, n.d.; and fragments from the libretto for Panurge.
  - Restricted Fragile
    - Folder 110, n.d.; 2 items. (Box Restricted Fragile Folder 1)
    - Folder 146, 1892; 1 item. (Box Restricted Fragile Folder 2)
    - Folder 184, n.d.; 1 item. (Box Restricted Fragile Folder 3)
    - Folder 199, 1959 Jun 26; 1 item. (Box Restricted Fragile Folder 4)
    - Folder 200, 1959-84; 3 items. (Box Restricted Fragile Folder 5)
- Mayr, Giovanni Simone, 1763-1845
  - Music
    - Carretto del venditore d'aceto
      Opera, with libretto by Giuseppe Foppa.
      First performed 1800.
      - "Venditor d'aceto", [circa 1800]; 1 ms. score ([396] p.); 23 x 30 cm. (Box Volume 39)
        Score, copyist's manuscript, with revisions, cuts, and other annotations possibly by Mayr.
        Title from spine.
        Pages numbered 1-198, rectos only.
        Pages cropped by binder, with some loss of music.
        Binding: contemporary red half calf.
- Méhul, Etienne Nicolas, 1763-1817
  - Correspondence
    - Unidentified, n.d.; 1 item (1 p.); 13 cm. (Box OVERSIZE FOLDER 24)
      Brief ALS accepting a dinner invitation.
      Mounted on a leaf with letter from Etienne Nicolas Méhul. English translations of letters, for which originals are not present, from Adolphe Adam to "Regnier," undated, and from Hector Berlioz to an unidentified recipient, undated, are on verso.
      Former group number: 53 MEHUL, ETIENNE NICOLAS
- Melba, Nellie, Dame, 1861-1931
  - Correspondence
    - Niedringhaus, Dorothy, ca. 1910; 1 item (1 p.); 21 cm. (Box Folder 318)
      ALS, [London], with envelope, about tickets for a performance.
      Former group number: 54 MELBA, NELLIE
      Gift of R. D. Clement Meier, 1961.
- Merrick, Joseph, active 1762-1763
  - Music
    - Joseph Merrick his singing book, 1762-1763; 1 v. of manuscript music (140, [8] p.); 10 x 15 cm. (Box Volume 66)
      Manuscript music book containing hymns and songs, vocal parts only, most for treble, countertenor, tenor, and bass. Most are identified by names of hymn tunes or Psalm numbers, and most are without texts. Songs with texts include "Elegy on the Death of Queen Mary" and "An Anthem to King George." Includes an index of titles.
      Title from back pastedown.
      Signed several times on back endpaper and pastedown by Joseph Merrick, also spelled Mirick, 1762-1763, and by Thankfull Merrick, undated.
      Acquired from an unknown source, 1897.
- Messager, André, 1853-1929
  - Music
    - Coups de roulis. Vocal score
      Operetta with a libretto by Albert Willemetz, based on a novel by Maurice Larrouy.
      Published 1928 (vocal score).
      Former group number: 86 MESSAGER, ANDRE
      - "Coups de roulis / Albert Willemetz; André Messager", [ca. 1928]; 1 ms. vocal score (ca. 180 p.); 35 cm. (Box Volume 20)
        Vocal score, with corrections by Messager and printer's markings for publication by Editions Salabert. Sections are numbered and paged separately; number twelve is not present. Accompanied by two documents identifying the score as Messager's holograph, signed by his granddaughter Jacqueline Dumore-Messager, 1971 May 23 and undated.
        Pl. no.: E.A.S.4583 (manuscript printer's annotation).
    - Passionnément. Vocal score
      Opera, with libretto by Maurice Hennequin and Albert Willemetz.
      First performed 1926; published 1926.
      - "Passionnément / Maurice Hennequin; Albert Willemetz; André Messager", [circa 1926]; 1 ms. vocal score ([circa 120] p.); 35 cm., in portfolio, 38 cm. (Box Volume 47)
        Vocal score, holograph, with revisions and printer's markings. The finale of act 3 is in copyist's manuscript.
        Title from cover of act 1.
        Purchased from Drouot Estimations (Drouot Estimations sale, 2003 April 2, lot 61) on the Library Associates Endowment Fund, 2003.
- Meyerbeer, Giacomo, 1791-1864
  - Correspondence
    - Célérier, Madame, n.d.; 1 item (2 p.); 21 cm. (Box Folder 319)
      ALS, concerning shawls sent by his wife, Minna Mosson Meyerbeer.
      Former group number: 55 MEYERBEER, GIACOMO
  - Music
    - Africaine. Vocal score
      Opera, with libretto by Eugène Scribe.
      Composition began in 1837; revision by François-Joseph Fétis after Meyerbeer's death in 1864; first performed 1865.
      - "L'Africaine: opéra en 5 actes / paroles de M. Scribe; musique de Giacomo Meyerbeer", 6 Novembre 1843; 1 ms. vocal score ([352] p.); 27 x 38 cm. (Box Volume 21)
        Vocal score, corrected, of Meyerbeer's first version of the opera, "terminé le 6 Novembre 1843".
        Purchased from Autographes on the Edith and Richard French Fund and the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
- Miles, Susanna, active 1759
  - Music
    - Susanna Miles her singing book, 1759; 1 v. of manuscript music (circa 20 leaves); 11 x 16 cm (Folder 453)
      Manuscript music book containing hymns and songs, vocal parts only, for treble and tenor. Most are identified by names of hymn tunes or Psalm numbers, and most are without texts. Songs with texts include "An Elegy Made on the Death of Queene Mary" and "King George's Anthem." Music is preceded by printed leaves titled "The Gamut or Scale of Musick," rules for "finding your Mi," and "Musical Characters" (no place, publisher, or date); and manuscript "Rules for Tuning the Voice."
      Acquired from an unknown source, 1921.
      Former call number: Z117 130
- Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791
  - Music
    - Entführung aus dem Serail
      Former group number: 56 MOZART, WOLFGANG AMADEUS
      - "Entführung aus dem Serail", [178-?]; 1 v. (482 p.) (Box Volume 22)
        Manuscript score in an unidentified hand. Accompanied by copies of letters from Prof. Leo Schrade and Donald G. Wing concerning the manuscript.
        Gift of Stanleigh P. Friedman, 1947.
- Neuville, V. (Valentin), 1863-1941
  - Music
    - Madeleine
      Opera, with libretto by Louis Payen.
      First performed in Brussels, 1901, and Lyon, 1906.
      Former group number: 57 NEUVILLE, V.
      - "Madeleine: pièce rustique en trois actes et quatre tableaux / musique de V. Neuville; poème de Louis Payen", 1900 Mar 8; 1 ms. score (383 p.); 35 cm. (Box Volume 23)
        Score, with conductor's markings, signed at end and dated at Lyon.
    - Notre Dame de Fourvières
      Oratorio with libretto by Eugène Vial.
      First performed by the société des Grands Concerts, directed by Georges-Martin Witkowski, Lyon, 1908.
      - "Notre Dame de Fourvières: oratorio pour rècitant, soli, choeurs, orgue, et orchestre / texte de E. Vial; musique de V. Neuville", 1905 Sep 8; 1 ms. score (385 p.); 37 cm. (Box Volume 24)
        Score, signed at end and dated at "Les Roches, Fête de la nativité de la Ste. Vierge."
- Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880
  - Correspondence
    - Unidentified, n.d.; 1 item (2 p.); 21 cm. (Box Folder 320)
      ALS to "Mon cher ami" asking for financial help.
      Stamped: "Autograph Collection of Dr. Max Thorek, Chicago."
      With engraved portrait of Offenbach.
      Former group number: 58 OFFENBACH, JACQUES
      Purchased from Argosy Book Store, Inc. on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
  - Music
    - Amour chanteur
      Opera, with libretto by Charles Nuitter and Ernest L'Epine. First performed 1864.
      - "L'amour chanteur", [circa 1864]; 1 ms. score ([6] p.); 27 x 34 cm., in binding, 28 x 36 cm. (Box Volume 51)
        Chanson and chorus beginning, "Que tout se taise en ma présence," score, holograph with revisions.
        Title from preliminary page, written in an unidentified hand.
        Purchased from Lisa Cox (Sotheby's sale, 2005 May 20, lot 120) on the Edith and Richard French Fund, 2005.
    - Baguette
      Opera, also titled Fédia, with libretto by Henri Meilhac and Ludovic Halévy.
      Begun in 1862; incomplete.
      - Sketches for La baguette, [1862]; 1 v. of ms. music ([circa 60] p.); 26 x 35 cm. (Box Volume 49)
        Sketches, holograph, for La baguette. Holograph annotations on endpapers include names and addresses; notes about composition and rehearsals for La baguette, dated 1862 November; and transcription of a poem by Julius Sturm. A few sketches for Les bavards (opera, with libretto by Charles Nuitter, after Cervantes's Los habladores; first performed 1862) are also present.
        Contains additional blank pages.
        Binding: contemporary calf-backed boards, by Lard-Esnault, Paris.
        Purchased from Bernard Quaritch, Ltd. (Sotheby's music sale, 2001 May 25, lot 147), on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2001.
    - Barbe-bleue
      Opera, with text by Henri Meilhac and Ludovic Halévy.
      First performed 1866.
      - Fragment possibly from Barbe-bleue, undated; 1 ms. score fragment ([4] p.); 27 x 35 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 74)
        Score fragment from an opera, holograph with revisions, with parts for "Bobeche" and "Nicolas," possibly for Barbe-bleue.
      - Sketches, undated; [2] p. of ms. music; 19 x 25 cm. (Box Folder 390)
        Brief sketches for Barbe-bleue and an unidentified vocal work, holograph.
        Accompanied by a holograph note from Zulma Bouffar to an unidentified recipient, undated, on a visting card.
        Purchased from L'Autographe on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2004.
    - Chants du crépuscule
      For violoncello and piano
      - Adieu, undated; 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 26 x 35 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 73)
        Purchased from Christie's (Rome sale, 2001 December 13, lot 394) on the Library Associates Endowment Fund, 2002.
        Also contains a fragment of Chants du crépuscule. Pas Villageois.
    - Cinq soeurs
      Set of waltzes for orchestra.
      Composed 1851.
      - "Les cinq soeurs", 1851 June 8; 1 ms. score (19 p.); 23 cm., in binding, 24 cm. (Box Volume 48)
        Score, holograph. Dated at end, 1851 June 8, Mont-Chartrain.
        Title from caption, written in an unidentified hand.
        Purchased from Bernard Quaritch, Ltd. (Sotheby's music sale, 2001 May 25, lot 146), on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2001.
    - Citrouillard au désert
      Oratorio for narrator, chorus, and orchestra; parody of Félicien David's Le désert.
      Composed in 1846.
      - "Le désert", [1846]; 1 ms. score ([76] p.); 32 cm., in binding, 33 cm. (Box Volume 50)
        Followed by a page fragment with unidentified sketches.
        Purchased from Bernard Quaritch, Ltd. (Sotheby's London sale, 2001 December 7, lot 138), on the Edith and Richard French Fund, 2002.
    - Le château à Toto
      First performed 1868.
      - "Le château: 2d acte, no. 5", [circa 1868]; 1 ms. score ([6] p.); 27 x 35 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 75)
        Duet for Tito and the Viscountess, from act 2, holograph score.
    - Unidentified
      - "Adieu"
        Related Materials
        See: Chants du crépuscule
      - Fragments of unidentified music, undated; [6] p. of ms music; 28 x 35 cm. and smaller (Box Oversize Folder 76)
        Score fragment of unidentified music for chorus of "bergers" and "bergères"and orchestra, beginning "Avec Lucas sous les charmilles je folâtrais," holograph with revisions; and unidentified sketches, holograph.
        Purchased from Pierre Berès (Drouot Richelieu sale, 2002 May 29, lot 41) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2002.
      - Sketches, undated; [3] p. of ms. music; 28 x 36 cm. and smaller (Box Oversize Folder 71)
        Unidentified sketches, holograph.
      - Sketches, undated; [3] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 72)
      - Sketches, undated; [2] p. of ms music; 36 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 77)
      - Sketches, undated; [2] p. of ms music; 27 x 34 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 79)
        Purchased from Lisa Cox (Cosmatos sale, 1998 March 31, lot 325) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 1998.
      - Sketches and fragments, undated; [circa 26] p. of ms. music; 36 cm. and smaller (Box Oversize Folder 78)
        Unidentified sketches and fragments, most holograph; some possibly in copyist's manuscript.
      - Sketches for vocal music, undated; [1] p. of ms. music; 14 x 25 cm. (Box Folder 391)
        Brief sketches for an unidentified vocal work, holograph.
        Purchased from Lisa Cox on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 1999.
- Paladilhe, Emile, 1844-1926
  - Music
    - Passant. Vocal score
      Opera, with libretto by François Coppeé.
      First performed 1872; vocal score published 1872.
      - Fragments from Le passant, [circa 1872]; 1 ms. vocal score ([36] p.); 36 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 80)
        Incomplete vocal score, holograph, with revisions and printer's markings.
        Plate numbers in manuscript: G. H. 814-G. H. 819 (G. Hartmann).
- Patti, Adelina, 1843-1919
  - Correspondence
    - Unidentified, 1895 Jun 14; 1 item (3 p.); 21 cm. (Box Folder 321)
      ALS, [London], to "Virginia," signed "Adelina Patti Nicolini," about Patti's success at Covent Garden.
      Formerly mounted in a scrapbook.
      Former group number: 59 PATTI, ADELINA
      Gift of Wilmarth S. Lewis, 1953.
- Pierné, Gabriel, 1863-1937
  - Correspondence
    - Unidentified, [1897?] Jun; 1 item (2 p.); 14 cm. (Box Folder 322)
      ALS, Paris, with address leaf, to "Madame," accepting an invitation.
      Former group number: 60 PIERNE, GABRIEL
      Purchased from Lisa Cox (Sotheby's, 2000 May 26, lot 2) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
  - Music
    - Intermezzo
      - "Intermezzo: partition d'orchestre / Gabriel Pierné", [1883]; 1 ms. score (37 l.); 36 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 81)
        Score, holograph, with revisions and printer's markings, signed at end. Accompanied by a transcription for solo piano, holograph, with printer's markings.
        Plate number in manuscript for score: 16973 R (Richault). Revised plate numbers in manuscript for score: 16998 R and 17489.
        Plate number in manuscript for parts: 16974 R (Richault). Revised plate numbers in manuscript for parts:16999 R and 17490.
        Plate number in manuscript for piano transcription: 16975 R (Richault).
        Purchased from Les Autographes on the Edith and Richard French Fund, 2003.
- Pizzetti, Ildebrando, 1880-1968
  - Correspondence
    - Jean-Aubry, Georges, 1908-23; 8 items. (Box Folder 323)
      Four ALS with envelopes and four autograph postcards signed to Jean-Aubry regarding Pizzetti's music and that of Albert Roussel.
      Former group number: 61 PIZZETTI, ILDEBRANDO
      Purchased from Christies (Int.) S. A. (Rome, 1998 Jun 9, lot 611) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
    - Unidentified, 1915, 1920; 2 items. (Box Folder 324)
      Two ALS regarding Pizzetti's music.
- Ponchielli, Amilcare, 1834-1886
  - Correspondence
    - Boselli, 1873 Dec 13; 1 item (2 p.); 21 cm., mounted on sheet, 39 cm. (Box OVERSIZE FOLDER 24)
      ALS, Milan, to Boselli, at the publisher Ricordi, Milan, asking for information about singers [Luigi?] Bolis and Armand Castelmary, and discussing Stefano Gobatti's I goti.
      Includes leaf with docketing information.
      Mounted on a leaf with notes about a letter, which is not present, from Dame Emma Albani. An English translation of a letter, for which the original is not present, from [Ferdinand?] Herold to "Mr. Milhes," undated, is on verso.
      Former group number: 62 PONCHIELLI, AMILCARE
  - Music
    - Marion Delorme
      Opera, with libretto by Henrico Golisciani, after Victor Hugo's Marion de Lorme.
      First performed 1885; published (vocal score, no date).
      - Fragment from Marion Delorme, [ca. 1885]; 1 item (2 p. of music); 38 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 28)
        Sketch fragment, in close score, beginning with the text, "Didier non vili pendermi".
        On verso is a sketch in full score, possibly from the same opera, with text, " ... giorno standera suma der pocce un Angiol stende ...".
    - I promessi sposi. Vocal score
      Opera, with libretto after Alessandro Manzoni. First performed 1856; revised 1872.
      - Fragment from I promessi sposi, 1856 [July 19?]; 1 ms. score fragment ([3] p.); 24 x 32 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 83)
        Vocal score fragment from scene and duet, act II, no. 6, with text beginning "Oh mio diletto abbracciami," holograph, signed.
        Plate number in manuscript: L0883.
    - Unidentified
      - Fragments from a mass, n.d.; 3 score fragments. (Box Folder 325)
        Three fragments of music, with corrections, signed, from an unidentified mass for solo voices, chorus, and keyboard. The fragments consist of part of a Kyrie, and two fragments of a Credo.